"Hong Kong in 1959"
"After sending his older son
Ip Ching to study in Foshan,"
"Ip Man lived in Hong Kong
with his wife and younger son."
"He taught Wing Chun
and promoted the martial arts."
Anyone want some snacks?
"Fifth floor"
Master Ip.
Morning!
So early?
Master Ip, it's me.
You don't recognise me?
Siu-long.
When I was little,
I asked you to teach me Kungfu.
You asked me to come again
when I grow up.
Please take me as a disciple.
Why should I accept you?
Because I will be
your greatest disciple.
Why are you so sure?
Because I'm fast.
How fast?
Not fast enough, kid.
Can you be faster?
That's pretty fast.
But did you really kick the water
or only think you did?
"Chiyan Primary School"
Fight! Fight!
Cheung Fong of Wing Chun.
Ip Ching of Wing Chun.
Keep quiet, stop it!
Let go.
I told you two not to fight.
Break the shell,
then remove the yolk.
What's with the ring?
The old folks say that adding silver
helps with bruising.
So, why were they fighting today?
It's always over
whose Kungfu is the best.
I should've kept an eye on them.
What a fight, they really got hurt.
It's Ching's fault, he's so naughty.
So, where is
this boy's father?
Cheung Fong is new here.
His dad picks him up quite late.
Fong, what does your dad do?
Is he always so busy?
Rickshaw puller.
Sorry, sorry.
-Sorry, Miss Wong.
-Master Ip.
I was busy at the Kungfu school
so I'm late.
Let me see.
Ching, what's this about?
Both kids were at fault in fact,
so I wanted
all the family heads here.
Right, is Fong's dad here yet?
I need to apologise to them.
No, like you, he's late.
No problem, work comes first.
-You can't eat it...
-Put it down.
The boy is hungry.
Miss Wong, how about this?
We'll give them dinner first,
and you will let his father
know about it.
-Is that okay?
-Okay.
Wing-sing, okay?
Of course.
Fong, are you okay
to have dinner with us?
Take your book bag.
-Take care.
-We're off.
-Thank you.
-You are very kind, Master Ip.
Sorry to trouble you.
-Thank you, Mrs Ip.
-Bye.
Bye.
Fong, eat up, don't be shy.
Yeah, Fong!
Make yourself at home, eat.
Eat up.
Darling, the fish is delicious.
Cheung Fong, not bad.
Who taught you?
My father, can you fight?
A little.
I'm Cheung Fong's father,
is my son here, please?
Yes, he is.
Nice to meet you, Mr Cheung.
Please, come in.
Fong, your father is here.
Master.
Fong.
Tell me what went on today.
The kids were naughty and fought.
They'll learn in time.
Come here, Ching.
Fong.
Aren't you going to apologise?
Ching is at fault too.
Ip Ching, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Cheung Fong.
Shake hands and now you're friends.
I've taken you out of your way.
I apologise, Mr Cheung.
Good to meet you, Master Ip.
I saw Fong working the wooden man.
He's good, he's been taught well.
You are too kind.
But it's late, you should rest.
I'll see you off.
Master,
Uncle Ip has a wooden man too.
Do you know him?
Yes, Uncle Ip is very famous.
But one day, I'll be more famous.
Which of you is better at Kungfu?
Who do you think?
You, of course!
Let's go.
Let me have a look, does it hurt?
No.
Hurry, get in!
It's about to start.
One at a time!
Bigger bets, bigger wins.
Move, out of the way.
Cheung Tin-chi!
Come forward, one by one!
Brother Sang!
-What?
-The boss is here.
Not bad, kid.
Go.
Keep going.
Hey, boss.
-Come on.
-Alright.
-Wait here, I'll be right back.
-Okay.
Boss.
Don't worry,
I've got it under control.
Money of these two weeks.
-Open it up, please.
-Okay.
You did good.
-Thank you.
-What about that other business?
The school?
No problem, give me one month.
No, two weeks.
Oh, come on...
Okay, I love a challenge.
Deal.
Remember, I want that school.
The rest means nothing without it.
Yes, understood.
What kind of Kungfu is that?
Wing Chun.
It's really powerful.
"Top Martial Arts School"
Martial artists come here every day,
to chat and drink tea.
Each school has its own table.
Master Tin.
-Master Chan, a rising star.
-Master Tin.
He has a lot of students.
Master Chan.
Now, this table is amazing,
the best of the best.
It's my table.
Master Tin.
Just kidding...
The real champions sit there,
the Wing Chun table.
Master Tin.
Lik, where's your master?
There he is.
Master Ip.
-Master.
-Master Tin, have you eaten?
-No, your treat?
-Of course!
You know Master Ip, of course?
-Master Ip, hello.
-Hello, how do you do?
-I'm Lee, hello.
-Hi, Mr Lee.
Lee is a good reporter
who keen to write about
the martial arts
and even want to
take photos of us too.
-Great.
-Is that okay with you, Master Ip?
-Of course.
-Thank you so much.
Master Lee, right here.
-Ip Man, the centre seat.
-No, no.
-It's yours.
-No, really.
No, it's fitting, sit down.
Master Ip, telephone.
Please don't reject me.
-I'll take that if it's okay.
-Sure.
We'll save your seat for sure.
We'll wait.
Did you forget our date?
Wasn't it for the 4th of this month?
For Thursday.
Is it for Thursday?
Oh, I'll rush right over.
I've been waiting an hour.
The dancing is almost finished
when you arrived,
so don't bother.
Just go pick up Ching
from school then.
Oh, I'm in trouble.
-Master Ip, please.
-Come on, sit here.
Here, in the centre.
-Okay, I give in.
-And why not?
Look sharp, eyes front, hold still!
Ready.
One, two, three.
-Master Ip.
-Hello.
Are you're here for your son?
Where's your wife?
She's busy today.
-And you're not?
-Sometimes.
Master Ip,
you look younger by the day.
Of course,
look how pretty his wife is.
You're right.
Such a lucky couple.
-Master Ip.
-Unlike me.
Mr Cheung.
Hello...
-Picking up your son?
-Yes.
Oh, right,
this medicine helps with bruises.
It's for your son.
Thank you, that's so nice.
How is Fong?
He's fine.
I'm glad.
Master Ip,
I hear you learned Wing Chun
from Chan Wah Shun, right?
Yes.
So we're schoolmates,
both from the school
of Foshan's Grandmaster Leung Jan.
So we are truly brothers-in-arms.
I heard that
Master Chan used fist and stick
better than swords and feet.
Is that true?
Each has their own
strengths and weaknesses,
It's normal.
How about you, Master Ip?
I'm just a dabbler.
If we have the chance,
let's have a friendly match.
Someday.
Bye, Miss!
-Master.
-Fong.
What did you learn today?
-Mathematics.
-Mathematics?
Chinese and English as well.
How did you do? Did you behave?
Yes.
-Have you ever been to school?
-Nope.
Dad, where's mom?
Principal,
these men are asking for you.
How may I help you?
-What are you doing?
-Move it!
-Sit, don't move!
-What are you looking at?
Fatty, calm down!
How can I talk over your noise?
So sorry, sir.
We gave you a fright.
-What's going on?
-Come, sit down.
Make room.
Sit down, and don't be afraid.
You're a scholar, I'm a gentleman.
We're reasonable people.
We help with development.
Sell your school to me
is a fair offer.
I'm not selling the school.
Won't you even read it first?
-Please have a look on it.
-I'm not selling.
These scholars are making a fuss.
Stop it!
How dare you not being obedient!
Watch out, Boss.
What's going on?
They're forcing me
to sell the school.
Think I don't know Kungfu?
Ip Man, what's with you?
It's just a business deal.
So, keep your nose out of it.
Hello,
this is Chiyan Primary School.
We need police here right now,
some thugs are causing trouble.
-Cut it out.
-Let my boss go.
Let my boss go or I'll whack her.
Let my boss go, now!
Please describe
what those three guys look like.
Those three just barged in
and began smashing things up.
Hong Kong seems prosperous,
but it's actually a mess.
More wealth means more crime.
You know my business.
Just like cyclops and their wife,
an eye is enough to watch about.
The truth is, we're understaffed
-and insanely busy everyday.
-You're right.
Hong Kong's crime rate is going up.
It seems pretty lawless.
No, we still have law.
Call the police and we come.
If we caught them red-handed,
they will be imprisoned.
Those idiots won't get away with it.
Yes...
We're relying on you, Sergeant Po.
Of course, it's my duty.
But Master Ip,
you know the score.
The police can't keep watch here
all day long,
so we need your help too.
-Just tell the people to be careful.
-I will.
Anything happens, call us.
-Great.
-I'll come straightaway, okay?
Thank you.
-You're welcome. Let's go, men.
-Yes, sir.
-See you.
-Take care.
Bye.
Ip Man.
You make me mad.
I'm gonna do you slowly.
David.
Brother Sang.
Chain up the school tonight.
Don't worry.
It'll be okay.
It's okay.
Principal!
-Miss Wong...
-Master Ip...
What's going on?
It was like this when I got here.
Will they demolish the school?
How will our kids get an education?
She's right.
Dad, open the gate.
I'll help you, careful.
Thank you.
You're really strong.
Can't I be skinny and strong?
Sure.
I'm big, but not that strong.
My name is Hui Lik.
They call me Miss Wong.
Call me if you need help.
"Chiyan Primary School"
Come on in.
Morning, granny.
Morning, and bye for now.
Master.
Let's go!
They'll be back for sure.
Then wait here for them tonight.
Okay.
-Tonight we're staying here.
-Good.
Miss Wong, nice meeting you again.
The school is off now?
Yes, can I help you?
Nothing.
May I ask, do you have a boyfriend?
No.
That's great.
Would you like a boyfriend?
I haven't thought about it.
Don't get me wrong,
but it's late now.
You shouldn't walk home alone.
I'm sorry.
Master Ip.
Hello, Miss Wong.
We've put you to a lot of trouble.
It's nothing.
Is my disciple giving you trouble?
No, Master Ip.
Not at all,
he kindly offered to see me home.
That's all it was, Master.
Why don't you see me home then?
Okay.
Hey, let's see Master Ip home
tonight.
Sure, it's pretty quiet.
Okay.
Master Ip,
you did a lot for us today.
You should get some rest.
I'm fine,
I didn't have any other plans.
Hurry.
Hurry up.
You guys, over there!
"Chiyan Primary School"
Help, Master Ip!
Protect Miss Wong!
-Okay?
-Yeah.
But we may not see you home.
-Up there!
-Okay.
Help!
Move.
Let's go, men.
We checked everywhere,
the fire's out.
-Make sure there's no live embers.
-Okay.
-Go double-check.
Master, the fire's extinguished,
but nothing's left but ash.
What a fire.
Principal, are you okay?
I'm fine.
But I underestimated those thugs.
Luckily, you and your men were here.
It was nothing...
Mr Cheung.
Thank goodness that you were there.
I was just passing by.
I've finally seen your Wing Chun.
It's as good as they say.
People are too nice.
If all's well,
I'll get back to work.
Bye.
The people want me to stay
and help guard the area.
It's an arson,
aren't the cops involved?
Yes, why wouldn't they be?
Fatty Po says
they'll crack the case.
We've no reason to doubt his word.
That's good, right?
But they can't give
24-hour protection, right?
So...
I might be out late
for a few nights.
Should I cook your dinner then?
Sure,
what will I eat otherwise?
Can't they do it without you?
It's not that,
but I will always help if I can.
It's working.
Then do me a favour, turn it off.
I am so sorry...
I was having dinner.
Come in and have a look.
Come, have a look.
The place has great fengshui,
it's an oasis in this busy district.
Well, the wall's a bit chipped,
but you can sweep it clean for good.
Fong, I'll open
my Kungfu school here.
You'll have lots of classmates then,
is that good?
Great, I'll be able to
practise here and here and here!
How much is a month's rent?
180 dollars,
water and electricity included.
I'll think it over, thank you.
Sir, the rent is negotiable.
You pull a rickshaw?
Why bother to check the place
and planning to run a school?
-You're wasting my time.
-Where to, boss?
Home.
Sir, this is my report
on the school arson case.
please see if there's any problem,
and I'll follow up
after you signed it.
Not necessary for this case now,
I'm handling it myself.
Why bother, sir?
It's jsut a small case,
which is too small for you, sir.
Let me handle it
and I will finish it good, alright?
Do you understand Chinese?
The investigation into the school,
I will take care of it.
Also, I am the one in charge here,
so get off.
Get out!
Yes, sir.
What's wrong with you?
Are you blind?
What's it to you?
You own the road?
Idiot.
You are at it again?
Small ball with banana oil...
Good, once again.
-Brother.
-Thanks.
Brother.
When I was buying breakfast
this morning,
people were saying that
we'd become security guards.
Why are you telling me this late?
Don't worry about it,
our master doesn't listen to gossip.
Who said it anyway?
Lots of people.
Would you recognise them?
Mantis?
"Chinese doctor, Ma Pak-leung"
How can I help you?
Well, I often have pain
in my abdomen.
-Do you have anything for it?
-Yes.
Crow And Phoenix Pills,
they help with blood circulation.
-Okay, I'll have a packet.
-Sure.
-Ip Man.
-Master.
Why didn't you tell me
-what happened?
-Have a seat.
They're saying at the teahouse,
you've become a security guard.
That's so insulting,
I bet Sang is the one
who was doing all these.
Have some tea.
I rue the day
that I made Sang my disciple.
He uses my Kungfu
to do awful things,
it's disgraceful!
He shames my school!
See, how could I tell you?
Well, I'm telling you,
I'll teach my own disciple a lesson!
I'm going after him.
Master Tin.
Master Tin, calm down.
Uncle Chan, I'll pay for this.
Master Tin.
Let Fatty Po handle it.
Too late for that,
I'll take care of this myself.
That guy owes me respect.
He's no longer your responsibility.
It's true that he left my school,
but I'm still his teacher.
Don't fret, I'll be fine.
Stop, what do you want?
I'm looking for Ma King-sang.
I'm his teacher, call him out.
"Chiyan Primary School"
Sergeant Po.
Lik, where's Master Ip?
Too late for that.
Master Tin was really furious.
Master Tin?
Now what?
Why are you here, Master Ip?
So I see my teacher,
what's it to you?
Master.
Sang.
Leave Master Ip out of this,
it's my idea to come here.
Stop causing so much trouble.
Leave those people alone,
give it up.
I always taught you
to do the right thing.
Look at yourself,
do you know what you look like now?
Dirty money and a pack of thugs,
do you think
that you are somebody now?
Think about it,
if you stop paying them,
would they still be there?
They bow and scrape
when you're around,
and calling you the foreign devil's
flunkey behind your back.
What? You want to fight me?
So I'm a flunkey,
a flunkey with money
is as good as a King.
And you?
A poor teacher so pure that
holding a broken umbrella in hand,
yet barely make a living!
Does that feel good?
You can't eat purity, can you?
Ask yourself, which of your students
still remember you
and cares about you?
All of them, they're with me now.
Idiot!
-Master Tin.
-Why do I have such disciples?
Leave it.
He's making me mad,
I'll teach him a lesson.
How dare you stab me?
You thug! You want to kill me?
Hurt me and you won't escape.
Men, over here!
"Western Union Dockyard"
Forward...
Let go of Sang!
Stop!
Don't worry about me.
Attack!
Fight, brothers!
Come on!
Let go of Sang!
Police, stop it!
Get back!
Go home.
Move and I'll shoot.
Ridiculous.
What's going on?
You playing with me?
Get out.
Say what?
Now you give the orders?
Know who owns this patch?
Are you gonna shoot me?
Well, so what?
What will you tell
your captain then?
Shut up or I'll arrest you.
I'll seal off this whole place.
See what you tell your boss then!
Don't believe me?
Just try me, you idiot!
What will you do about the school?
Sang's boss
has my captain in his pocket.
The two foreign devils
are in cahoots,
who are about
to fool everyone around.
It's hopeless, the school is doomed.
Fatty, I trust in you
because you're not like other cops.
But only one word from a foreigner,
and you drop the case?
It's not that,
but I just can't help with it.
So you didn't arrest the arsonist,
nor looking after
the community and the kids?
And now my disciples
are even doing your work for you.
What else can I do?
Master Ip, you're a fighter,
but still not a God.
You can't change the rules.
You can guard the school
day and night now,
but for how much longer then?
You know foreign devils
run Hong Kong.
The world's not fair.
But moral standards
shall apply to all equally.
The ruler
isn't always a superior person,
while the one being ruled
isn't always inferior either.
The world doesn't belong to the rich
nor even the powerful,
but to those with a pure heart.
Have you thought of the children?
All that we do, they're watching.
We need to be good role models.
All that we do is not for today,
but for the better future.
"Toss it if you don't want it"
"Please sew on the button"
Mrs Ip, after my initial diagnosis,
a tumour is what I suspected,
and there will be a decline
in the future.
We'll learn more
once having the full report,
so please not to
worry too much for now.
Master Ip...
We all pitched in for the soup.
-Enjoy it.
-Thank you.
Thanks to you, Master Ip.
We'll do something for you.
Great, great, another win.
You fight a lot, what's the deal?
-Do you in a need?
-Only for a living.
I need to eat too.
You hurt my men at the school,
and owe me one that time.
How much do I owe?
It's not about that.
I admire you,
and I wanna be your friend.
Sang, what's this about?
What I mean is that
as your humble friend,
I was being pushed over to the wall
by another man.
So, I'm buying
one of the man's hand here.
You've so many men,
why do you need me?
Because he knows Kungfu
and so do you,
not to mention that you fight well.
And if I say no?
Then, please go elsewhere
for a crust.
Alright...
Hand it over.
Sang,
That money, I want it all.
"Yeung's Umbrella Repairing Shop"
"Just be prepared for anytime,
and there's nothing to be scared of"
How many more days of this?
You're up?
I didn't want to wake you.
Just a few more days.
-When will we have dinner together?
-Tonight.
I'll come back earlier tonight.
Are you okay?
Well...
-Hello.
-Hello, are you Mr Ip?
Yes, who's this?
This is from Kowloon Hospital.
What is it?
Master Tin has been badly wounded
and being sent to our hospital,
who wants to see you now.
Okay, I'll be right there.
I have made the call to Mr Ip.
Thank you.
"Ward"
-Let's get to work.
-Sure.
Very good.
Go play.
Nice, again.
Thank you.
I know that it was Sang
who sent him to me for sure.
As a teacher, I'm a total failure.
This tastes so good.
-Let's get some!
-Yes, this one!
Kids,
I have some cartoon slides,
do you want to see them?
It's free.
Come on.
-Hey, what are you doing?
-Get going!
Let them go!
Help me.
He's heavy.
What are you doing?
-Enjoy yourself.
-Help me.
Help!
You've got two hours to get
the principal to the shipyard,
or I will sell those kids
into slavery overseas.
How did you know I was in hospital?
You told them to call me.
-No, I didn't.
-You didn't?
Mrs Ip, where's Master Ip?
What is it?
Tell me, what happened?
Master Ip!
What is it, Miss Wong?
It is about Ching,
Fong and other kids,
a man abducted them!.
What?
If the principal doesn't
go to see him in two hours,
he'll sell the children
into slavery overseas!
Hurry, go find the principal now,
-then tell Sergeant Po about it.
-Yes.
Well.
I want the principal
and you bring a stick instead.
Just great.
Where is the principal?
On his way.
So let the kids go first, okay?
Dad!
Shut up!
Son, don't be afraid.
I'm here.
So this is your son, doesn't he?
Luckily, I was hoping to get him.
Let him out.
Stand straight and calm down.
Kid, come here.
Sang, the kid have nothing
to do with this,
so don't you mess with him, okay?
Why would I mess with him?
I'm just giving him an apple.
Don't be afraid,
and feel free to have some apple.
Well...
we can only talk after your father
putting down the stick.
Ching, don't be afraid.
Put down the pole.
Act like you mean it.
On your knees.
Kowtow.
Hey, what are you doing here?
There's no fight today.
You took my boy.
Master!
Help me!
Fong.
So he's your boy?
Sorry, he's one of ours.a
Just let him go.
Luckily, it was me who took him.
or anything bad could've happened.
Leave it alone, and just go!
Ip Man,
you're a good fighter, yes?
I heard that you can
take on ten men, is that right?
Don't say
I didn't give you a chance.
One against eleven...
With every punch you land,
I'll give him a piece to eat.
Master, they still have my friends.
Why are you back?
To pick the kids up from school.
Don't come close.
Another step and I'll kill him.
Dad!
Bite him.
Go!
Don't let him run away.
Run!
Get the kid, quick!
Over there, quick!
Dad!
David, don't just stand there!
Go grab that kid!
Dad!
-Kneel!
-Don't move!
Hear me?
-I'm not with them...
-Kneel!
Don't move, no one move!
Kneel!
We are police, don't move!
Just go in and take photos.
Don't move!
Take as many photos as you can...
Great headline material.
Let these journalists take photos,
and it'll be tomorrow's news.
I said kneel, understand?
You idiot!
I said don't move, how dare you!
Don't move!
Kneel!
Hands on the head and kneel!
Mom!
Ching!
There was trouble at the school.
They abducted Ching.
I'm so sorry, Wing-sing.
It's my fault
I was wrong.
It's my fault.
It won't happen again, okay?
Go wash your face.
-Okay.
-Good kid.
It's all my fault.
Don't cry.
Darling, I'm so afraid.
It's all right now.
But I might not be.
What do you mean?
The doctor said
that I probably...
have cancer.
The black spots
indicate cancer cells,
which also be known as tumours.
The cancer has spread too widely
that we just can't help
with any operation.
Is it curable?
Normally, we'd prescribe medicines.
But at this stage, they're unlikely
to get it under control now.
Doctor, how much time do I have?
Around six months.
I'll get you more rice.
Just half.
Don't worry, you're safe.
The police are on your side.
But there's always new story
in the paper everyday,
about abducted children or people
being thrown from their homes.
My boss will be unhappy with it.
And I will be unhappy either
if my boss doesn't so.
So, for the time being all this,
nefarious vice and corruption
that you love to engage yourself in
are what you have to take a hiatus.
Otherwise, Frankie,
I can't protect you.
-Whatever you say.
-Yes.
Well, Frankie,
these chats are always a pleasure.
Cheerio.
Boss, this Thai guy's incredible.
Elbows, knees, fists, all great.
Put it up.
It's my mistake, Boss.
I have never thought
that it will end up like this.
I just meant to
give the principal a scare,
but not creating such a mess.
That Ip Man, it's all his fault.
I'm sorry.
I don't ever want to
see your face again.
Get away!
Ip Man.
Finish him off!
"Chinese doctor, Yim Ching-hua"
Get out.
Want any tea?
Listen, things about the school
have quieted down.
I'm not expecting more trouble,
so you can be at ease now.
But be careful,
the foreign devils can't be trusted.
Sang's boss has it out for you,
so watch out.
Come on, speed up!
Right?
You're good.
Hello, uncle.
You want me, that's why I'm here.
What do you want?
So you're Ip Man?
You're the best fighter in China?
Interesting.
Okay, let's deal.
It seems your Wing Chun
is the fastest,
which so fast to be invincible.
Let's see whose fists
are the fastest of all.
Is it yours?
Or mine?
Three minutes.
If you last by then,
I'll let you be.
Mom!
Come here.
Hey, how you doing?
Can you get my balloon back?
Let it go, don't worry about it.
Get you a new one, okay?
A new balloon.
Madame, here's my rent.
I always said you'd come good!
Best of luck!
You'll be raking it in!
Great,
I can practice Wing Chun here then!
Master, respect!
Respect!
Sir, you teach Wing Chun?
You must know Ip Man, right?
Look, this is today's newspaper,
and Ip Man is in the news.
He's so impressive, see?
I bet you two are great friends
since both of you teach Wing Chun.
Please introduce me
to him sometimes.
Here's the key,
and I'll leave you here alone.
Don't forget to introduce me!
Did you write this?
"Wing Chun's Ip Man
helps police to rescue the kids"
Yes.
My name is Cheung Tin-chi.
I'm also a Wing Chun fighter,
can you write about me too?
I've seen Ip Man's Kungfu,
that's not authentic Wing Chun.
I'll challenge him
to a public match.
All the Kungfu schools
respect Ip Man's Wing Chun.
Even if I write something,
we'll have to see
if the Kungfu world
think you're qualified
to publicly challenge Master Ip.
Have a seat, Master.
Got your camera?
Nice tea today.
Cheung of Wing Chun,
a friendly match?
Who are you?
"Cheung Tin-chi
Bursts Into Kungfu Scene"
"Wing Chun Triumphant,
Cheung Tin-chi's Fame Spreads"
"New Kungfu King,
Cheung Tin-chi of Wing Chun"
"Cheung Tin-chi's
Wing Chun Martial Arts School"
Now, am I qualified?
Sure.
Master Cheung...
Congratulations, Master Cheung.
Eyes front, please.
Mr Wong,
thanks you for your support.
I admire a fighter with guts
and ambition.
If I can be of help,
just say the word.
Thank you.
Master Cheung.
You're fighting everyone recently
and even taking photographers along,
don't you worry people will talk?
I know lots of people think
I'm a show-off that I act superior.
But in Kungfu,
you do need to establish ranks.
And there is one thing
that I want to tell people.
Ip Man
don't have what it takes
to represent Wing Chun.
Gentlemen,
I hereby announce that
I'm challenging Ip Man to a fight!
"The Authentic Wing Chun"
Special news!
Wing Chun versus Wing Chun.
-Get your paper.
-I'll have one.
"Cheung Tin-chi Challenges Ip Man
in public"
"Which is authentic Wing Chun?"
"Two Jokes of A Day"
Darling, it's so ridiculous.
It's like the joke about Mo,
and all of his friends
are in a low spirit as well.
He says, "We're all henpecked."
"Want proof?"
"If your wife is the boss,
sit over there."
All the men just went over
with their heads held low,
while only Mo stayed where he was.
They said,
"Mo, you're the man
who is so fearless!"
Know what Mo said?
He said,
"Well, my wife told me"
"not to sit in crowded places."
Funny, right?
Are you scared of your wife?
Sometimes.
Next.
Are you Cheung Wing-sing?
Why would women
be made pretty but naive?
They're pretty,
so that men will like them.
They're so naive
that who will fall for men.
Look, someone's challenging Ip Man,
-When?
-Next month, on the 15th.
Harder.
Relax the shoulders, punch fast.
This way, Master Cheung.
I want to sit there.
"Master Ip"
Excuse me.
Master Ip, what are you doing here?
I'm looking for Mr Chan.
You want to learn to dance?
I dance better than him.
I'll teach you how to dance,
and you teach me Kungfu instead.
Sure, starting now?
Okay.
Why didn't you accept me
as a disciple last time?
You got it all wrong,
I didn't say I wouldn't accept you.
I didn't mean for you to leave
when I open the door back then.
"14th, Wednesday"
"15th, Thursday"
"Cheung Tin-chi's
Wing Chun Martial Arts School"
Wing Chun versus Wing Chun,
who's the authentic one?
It's an historic day for Wing Chun,
which will be like
a battle of dragons!
This is it,
is Ip Man the greater fighter?
Or is Cheung Tin-chi fiercer still?
Who represents the true Wing Chun?
The contest will begin
at 3:00 pm today,
let's wait with bated breath.
Sergeant Po!
-Where's Master Ip?
-No idea!
What's the problem?
Where is he? Does he get lost?
Relax, Ip Man won't let us down.
Let's do this.
Look.
It's time...
Where's your master?
Gentlemen, the match was
scheduled at 3:00 pm.
Since Ip Man has failed to show up,
I hereby announce
the victor and true spirit
of Wing Chun is...
Cheung Tin-chi.
Dad!
We won!
There's been no fight!
Maybe he's stuck in traffic?
And this makes you a grandmaster?
Master Cheung,
Ip Man's no-show today,
how would you comment it?
To mess with classic Wing Chun,
which just mean losing
the forefathers' vision of it.
For what shouldn't have been here,
shall never be there forever.
So that our forefathers don't need
to worry about the form's future.
I believe that
Master Ip understands this,
so he chose to forfeit the fight.
This is also an act of great merit.
From today,
I, Cheung Tin-chi,
will lead the true Wing Chun
to a glorious future.
-Bravo.
-True Wing Chun.
What did you say?
You've no right to that claim,
you aren't qualified
to fight my master!
-Settle down, stop.
-Stop.
Wing-sing!
Please, someone call an ambulance!
Mr Ip, her condition is worsening.
She needs to stay in hospital
for a bit.
How are you now? Feeling any better?
When can we go home?
The doctor said
it's better for you to stay here,
you need rest.
Is that 473?
It is 85?
Yeah, you are right.
"To Mr Cheung Tin-chi"
Give the letter to Cheung Fong
and tell him to give it to his dad.
Okay.
Nurse!
What it is it, madam?
Are you in pain?
Don't worry, I'll get the doctor.
Have some pigeon soup.
It's good for you.
Darling.
I want a photograph
with you out there.
You spend every day with me,
which makes me so happy.
But, I know I could be happier.
People say,
"Life belongs to you,
and it doesn't at the same time."
I didn't get it before.
But now, I'm beginning to.
You belong to yourself,
and so to this family,
as well as to this place as well.
But there are things you should do,
I don't want you to have regrets
only because of me.
I only regret that
I didn't being good enough to you.
But I think you've already been
so great to me.
If it wasn't for my sickness,
would you have taken the challenge?
Yes.
That's the Ip Man I love.
I am sorry, Man.
I've taken the liberty
of setting the date with him.
And I haven't heard about the sound
of your practise for ages,
can you please
let me hear that again?
"Cheung Tin-chi's
Wing Chun Martial Arts School"
"Shrine of the forefathers
of the authentic Wing Chun"
"The Authentic Wing Chun"
Wing Chun, Cheung Tin-chi.
Wing Chun, Ip Man.
"The Authentic Wing Chun"
-Ip Ching, come on.
-Okay.
"The Authentic Wing Chun"
I admit defeat,
and there's nothing more important
than the love of those by your side.
"Ip Man's wife Cheung Wing-sing"
"passed away in 1960 from cancer."
"Ip Man taught Ip Ching Wing Chun,"
"who guided the other's life
with martial arts"
"and became a grandmaster then."
"Wing Chun has been passing down
generation after generation,"
"which flourished
while spreading across the world."